# **Mark Reilly**

82 Plymouth Avenue, Maplewood, NJ 07040 • mark@alienresident.net • 347 228 3696

# **Summary**

I am a User Experience Designer with over fifteen years in interactive media. My career spans the breadth of digital production, from production art to web design and front-end development. As a User Experience Designer, my in depth understanding of the design process allows me to meet user goals while balancing aesthetics and technical constraints.

# **Professional Experience**

### **New York University**

October 2008-present

#### **User Experience Specialist**

Digital Communications Group, Information Technology Services August 2014–present

- Create a new responsive user interface for Sakai, an Open Source Learning Management System
- Commit back the user experience work from NYU Classes to Sakai
- Design a new user interface for NYU's *Email Direct* a bulk email communication tool for NYU administrators

#### **User Experience Designer**

Academic Technology Services, Information Technology Services
October 2011–August 2014

- Design a new user interface for NYU Classes the Learning Management System (LMS) based on extensive usability testing
- Create a 'Mobile First' prototype for our redesign of MediaCommons a digital network for professors and post-graduate students of film and media studies

#### **Interactive Designer and Developer**

Faculty Technology Services, Information Technology Services
October 2008–October 2011

- Design and develop <u>MediaCommons</u> a digital network for professors and post-graduate students — using Drupal
- Establish a distinctive look and feel for the MediaCommons network and it's project sites
- Design and develop book and photo viewing websites, and streaming audio and video for the NYU Libraries' special digital collections

#### **UX/UI Skills**

Usability Testing, User Interviews, and Personas • Sketching, Storyboarding, and Paper Prototyping • Wireframing, Card Sorting, and High-fidelity Prototyping • Markup (HTML) and Styling (CSS) • Visual Design, Style Guides, and Style Tiles • Typography and Graphic Production

#### **Technical Skills**

Photoshop, OmniGraffle,
Illustrator, Flash, Fireworks •
TextMate, HTML, CSS, Sass &
Compass, Javascript & jQuery, •
SVN & Git, PHP, MySQL, Drupal

# **Columbia University**

August 2001-September 2008

#### **Senior Web Designer and Developer**

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures (a small 'digital agency' within Columbia University) May 2005–September 2008

- Create educational course content and departmental websites for Columbia University and affiliated non-profits
- Design and develop websites using open source content management systems and static html

#### Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures August 2001–May 2005

- Work with Columbia Faculty to design and develop interactive eseminars and courses
- Design and develop interactive maps, audio slideshows, podcasts, and basic video production and post-production for streaming video and DVD

### **European Graduate School**

Fall 1999-Summer 2008

#### **Assistant Director for Web Design and Development**

Dept. of Media and Communications

- Establish a visual identity for a new university and a strong online presence
- Design, develop, and maintain the European Graduate School's website

#### **Scholastic**

January 2000-May 2001

#### Web Designer

e-Scholastic

- Design educational, commercial, and promotional websites for Scholastic
- Design daily site graphics, flash based interactive quizzes and educational activities

### Thirteen, WNET

1998-1999

#### **Production Artist and Animator**

Heritage Project DVD-ROM

 Produce over 500 interactive maps for an DVD-ROM historical atlas feature of the award winning Jewish history television series, "The Heritage Project"

## **Education**

1999–2007 Ph.D. Media & Communication, European Graduate School, Saas-Fee, Switzerland

1998-2001 Certificate in Film Production, The New School, New York, NY

1995-1996 M.Phil. Medieval History, Trinity College, Dublin University, Ireland

1991-1994 B.A. History and Philosophy, University College Dublin, Ireland